Ladies and gentlemen, here are 10 things that are truly awesome. Imagine, if you will, having to schlep everything on your back. Wouldn't this be easier for me if I could roll this home? Yes, so I think I'll invent the wheel. The wheel, ladies and gentlemen. Is the wheel awesome? Say it with me. Yes, the wheel is awesome! The Great Pyramids were the tallest man-made structure in the world for 4,000 years. Pharaoh had his slaves move millions of blocks just to this site to erect a big freaking headstone. Were the Great Pyramids awesome? Yes, the pyramids were awesome. The Grand Canyon. Come on. It's almost 80 million years old. Is the Grand Canyon awesome? Yes, the Grand Canyon is. Louis Daguerre invented photography in 1829, and earlier today, when you whipped out your smartphone and you took a shot of your awesome sandwich, and you know who you are — (Laughter) — wasn't that easier than exposing the image to copper plates coated with iodized silver? I mean, come on. Is photography awesome? Yes, photography is awesome. D-Day, June 6, 1944, the Allied invasion of Normandy, the largest amphibious invasion in world history. Was D-Day awesome? Yes, it was awesome. Did you eat food today? Did you eat? Then you can thank the honeybee, that's the one, because if crops aren't pollinated, we can't grow food, and then we're all going to die. It's just like that. But it's not like a flower can just get up and have sex with another flower, although that would be awesome. (Laughter) Bees are awesome. Are you kidding me? Landing on the moon! Come on! Apollo 11. Are you kidding me? Sixty-six years after the Wright Brothers took off from Kitty Hawk, North Carolina, Neil Armstrong was 240,000 miles away. That's like from here to the moon. (Laughter) That's one small step for a man, one giant leap for awesome! You're damn right, it was. Woodstock, 1969: Rolling Stone Magazine said this changed the history of rock and roll. Tickets were only 24 dollars back then. You can't even buy a freaking t-shirt for that now. Jimi Hendrix's version of "The Star-Spangled Banner" was the most iconic. Was Woodstock awesome? Yes, it was awesome. Sharks! They're at the top of the food chain. Sharks have multiple rows of teeth that grow in their jaw and they move forward like a conveyor belt. Some sharks can lose 30,000 teeth in their lifetime. Does awesome inspire fear? Oh, hell yeah, sharks are awesome! The Internet was born in 1982 and it instantly took over global communication, and later tonight, when all these PowerPoints are uplifted to the Internet so that a guy in Siberia can get drunk and watch this crap, the Internet is awesome. And finally, finally some of you can't wait to come up and tell me how awesome my PowerPoint was. I will save you the time. It was not awesome, but it was true, and I hope it was entertaining, and out of all the audiences I've ever had, y'all are the most recent. Thank you and good night. (Applause)
Damas y caballeros, estas son 10 cosas realmente asombrosas. Imaginen, si lo desean, que tienen que cargar todo en sus espaldas. ¿No sería más fácil para mí si pudiera hacer rodar esto a casa? Sí, por eso inventaré la rueda. La rueda, damas y caballeros. ¿Es la rueda algo asombroso? Repitan conmigo. Sí, ¡la rueda es algo asombroso! Las grandes pirámides fueron las estructuras hechas por el hombre más altas del mundo durante 4000 años. El faraón tenía esclavos que movían millones de bloques hasta este sitio para erigir esta bendita lápida. ¿Fueron las grandes pirámides algo asombroso? Sí, las pirámides fueron algo asombroso. El Gran Cañón. Vamos. Tiene casi 80 millones de años. El Gran Cañón ¿es algo asombroso? Sí, el Gran Cañón es asombroso. Louis Daguerre inventó la fotografía en 1829, y hoy más temprano, cuando sacaron sus teléfonos inteligentes y tomaron una foto de sus sándwiches asombrosos, —Uds. saben quiénes fueron— (Risas) ¿no fue más fácil que la exposición de la imagen a placas de cobre recubiertas con plata yodada? Digo, vamos. ¿La fotografía es algo asombroso? Sí, lo es. El Día D, 6 de junio de 1944, la invasión aliada de Normandía, la invasión anfibia más grande de la historia mundial. ¿El Día D fue algo asombroso? Sí, fue asombroso. ¿Se alimentaron hoy? ¿Comieron? Entonces pueden agradecerle a las abejas porque si no polinizaran los cultivos, no produciríamos alimentos, y moriríamos todos. Así de simple. Una flor no puede levantarse y tener sexo con otra flor, eso sí sería asombroso. (Risas) Las abejas son asombrosas. ¿Es una broma? ¡El alunizaje! ¡Vamos! La Apolo 11 ¿es una broma? 66 años después de que los hermanos Wright despegaran de Kitty Hawk, Carolina del Norte, Neil Armstrong estaba a 384 000 kilómetros. Una distancia como de aquí a la luna. (Risas) Fue un pequeño paso para el hombre, ¡un gran paso para el asombro! Tienen toda la razón, lo fue. Woodstock, 1969: la revista Rolling Stone dijo: Esto cambió la historia del rock and roll. En ese entonces las entradas costaban USD 24. Hoy no compramos ni una camiseta con ese dinero. La versión de Jimi Hendrix de The Star-Spangled Banner fue un ícono. Woodstock ¿fue asombroso? Sí, fue asombroso. ¡Los tiburones! Están en la cima de la cadena alimentaria. Tienen varias filas de dientes en sus mandíbulas y avanzan como una cinta transportadora. Algunos tiburones pueden perder 30 000 dientes a lo largo de sus vidas. ¿Lo asombroso inspira temor? Claro que sí, ¡los tiburones son asombrosos! Internet nació en 1982 y de inmediato se apoderó de la comunicación mundial, y, esta noche, cuando subamos estas presentaciones a Internet, ese tipo siberiano podrá emborracharse y mirar esta basura; ¡Internet es algo asombroso! Para terminar, muchos de Uds. no verán la hora de venir a decirme lo asombrosa que fue esta presentación. Les ahorraré tiempo. No fue asombrosa, pero fue verdadera, y espero que entretenida, y de todos los públicos que he tenido, Uds. son el más reciente. Gracias y buenas noches. (Aplausos)